

# **BEN FOK**

#### FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER | SENIOR LEADER | PROFESSIONAL COACH

A web developer of a different kind. I offer a compelling blend of technical skills, with over a decade of experience as a senior operational leader, strategic director, and educator. This positions me uniquely as an engineer who understands both the role of intuitive tech within the customer experience, and one who can speak the language of the web and that of your team and your business, to produce applications that drive results.

benfok8@gmail.com



(530)314-1419



Leavenworth, WA



benfok.github.io/portfolio1



github.com/benfok



linkedin.com/in/benfok

# TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML5

CSS3

**JavaScript** 

Node.js

React.js

**jQuery** 

MS 365 and Office

**Rest APIs** 

Articulate 360

SuccessFactors

Adobe Workfront

GitHub

"I have done some of my most enjoyable and mentally stimulating work with Ben" -Senior coworker

"I find Ben inspiring because he just comes up with good stuff! No BS, just accuracy in content and attention to detail which is great!" -Senior coworker

"Ben finds the potential in others and creates space for them the thrive. He is genuine and leads with kindness" -Former employee

# INTERESTS











## WORK EXPERIENCE

#### CEO | TIDY LINES LLC

November 2021 - Present

- o Freelancing web development, copy writing and project management.
- o Currently contracted by Vail Resorts; a multi-billion-dollar company in the leisure, hospitality and ski resort industry, for project management, copy writing and digital content management, issue resolution and consulting across 34 websites.
- o Improved workflow efficiency and reduced issue resolution time by over 30%.
- Consistently approached as a sounding board for ideas and for QA due to my attention to detail and experience working on both the end user and central domains.
- o Project Lead for digital migration for 3 new acquisitions beginning April '22.
- Coding examples can be found through my GitHub profile

#### Director of Skier Services | Stevens Pass, Vail Resorts

October 2013 - November 2021

- Director of operations for departments totaling 400+ employees and over \$4M in direct revenue. Doubled revenue in a 5-year period prior to COVID-19.
- o Resort project lead and SME on development of an industry leading custom ecommerce platform and annually responsible for delivering on capital projects totaling up to \$500K, such as complete remodel of rental facility in 2019.
- Created a deployed a critical thinking model companywide (40K employees) to improve decision making and reduce work safety incidents by up to 75%.
- o Designed and executed leadership training and employee orientation for all resort staff (800+) and management annually.
- o Recognized nationally for my leadership skills and business impact.

[SNOW Operating Platinum Award Winner 2017 | NSAA Conversion Cup Runner up 2016, 2017 and 2018 | Vail Resorts Camp II graduate in 2021 | Member of NSAA Growth Committee | Former consulting clients include Mt Hood Meadows Ski Resort, OR and Mtn High Resort, CA]

### **EDUCATION & TRAINING**

#### **Full Stack Web Developer Boot Camp**

University of Washington – Graduating May 2022

JavaScript, Asynchronous JavaScript and Node.js

Codecademy.com

#### Level 3 Alpine Ski Instructor & former Northwest Technical Team Member

Professional Ski Instructors of America – Since 2006

#### **Business, Physics and Statistics**

Chepstow Comprehensive, Wales U.K - 1997-2003